All right, now I'm
going to show you
how to plan a
news video. And news
is views, baby. So
what is a news
video? Well, it's basically
just reporting news in
your niche and giving
your take on it.
So here we have
a client, Tom, 300
,000 views on his
Trump video. And then
here we have another
client, Peter, who very
smartly wrapped up something
as news. So Apple's
awesome Apple Note features
that help you remember
anything. So it kind
of sounds new. It's
not necessarily new, but
he's kind of harnessing
news there because it's
new information. All right,
so the pros of
news can be very
fast to produce. In
fact, we're going to
find out why they
have to be fast
to produce in a
minute. Massive upside if
a big story explodes.
You can get a
lot of views very
fast. It's great for
kind of like widening
your audience. And it's
very easy to rank
and get suggested next
to similar content. If
a news story breaks,
YouTube's just going to
push that news story
that people are interested
in. Cons, views die
off fast. News is
never really evergreen. Views
are unpopular. Not only
as big as your
story. So if it's
a small story, you
get small views. If
you're jumping on a
news story like Tom
did, you've got about
24 hours to get
it turned around. So
that's why you have
to produce them quick.
So who should make
these? All creator levels,
if you can harness
news. Don't go looking
for it, going, oh,
where's there a news
story? A good news
story is one where
you're like, holy crap,
this is a big
deal because it will
have a lot of
interest. If you're in
a fast moving niche,
if you're in like
tech, AI, finance, health,
politics, harness that bad
boy. If you're an
expert. You can add
insights and give clarity
on the breaking story.
This is for you.
Types of viewers that
love them. Trend seekers
who want to stay
ahead of the curve.
Curious minds who are
a bit overwhelmed by
the noise. Look at
some clarity. Decision makers
who want to understand
how the news affects
them. So I think
investors create as professionals.
Best used to piggyback
on trending headlines for
fast traffic to build
topical authority in your
niche. Basically, if you
do news, link back
to a video optimized
for email signups or
sales or one that's
a really strong performer
for your channel. Or
one that's a really
strong performer for your
channel. So we can
take all these new
people who came for
the news and turn
them into a use
fan instead. News versus
use. Oh God. The
secret sauce, speed, get
out fast and adding
a unique point of
view. Mistakes, waiting too
long to publish. If
you publish a news
video too late, it's
not the news anymore.
It's the olds. If
you overload the view
of too much information
or jargon. If you're
forgetting to link the
story back to your
viewers world. So you
need to relate it
back to like, here's
why it matters to
you. So the strategy
is pretty simple. You
say what happened. You
tell the viewers why
it matters. To them.
And then you give
us your insights on
what to do next.
So if we break
it down like this,
we have our intro.
Here's what happened. That's
storytelling. Here's why it
matters to you. This
is the emotion brick.
Here's what you should
do about it. Given
the logical steps. That's
it. It's pretty easy.
I've been in titles
void. Like tight was
like big changes in
tech this week. They're
really vague. You need
to be specific. So
open AI just did
something that means the
whole world's going to
die.
Apple just killed X.
Are you ready? You
can see these titles
here. Don't go using
them. They're just examples.
And then for thumbnails
stick to results, curiosity
or cognitive dissonance best
here. And make sure
you show the thing
that is relevant to
the news story in
the thumbnail production. Keep
it simple. Don't over
edit. Just get the
content out fast. Not
perfect. And the intro,
you just hook them.
You set up the
problem that the news
might have caused or
the result it could
give the viewer. And
you set up what
you're going to cover
in the video. You
give your credibility statement.
So people go, this
person's qualified. I'm qualified
to tell me this
information and make sure
you match those viewers
expectation. And that's it.
If you optimizing, if
your goal is views,
push to another video
that isn't news based,
that perform well, that
you think would be
a great second video
for someone new to
your channel to discover.
If you're optimizing for
sales, push to high
converting sales. If you're
optimizing for email, push
to high converting video
for email. All right.
So here's my little
template to help you
plan a news story.
Set your goal. It's
unlikely you're going to
make sales from news.
So I'd always optimize
for emails or views
here. Complete your thumbnail
and title fast. Keep
it simple. Work out
your viewers. Top three
questions. Do your messy
brain dump. So what
happened? Why it matters.
What viewers should do
about it. If other
videos are already out
there, use skyscraper bot
to do the research.
Then define that messy
plan into points. Then
think of your conversion
strategy. Make sure you've
got your call to
action to email in
there. If that's what
you want. And then
move on to writing
that bad boy. If
you have no time
to write, I give
you permission to present
from bullets from your
refined plan. Speed really
does matter here. Upload
and track. And then
go. Did it hit
my goal? Repeat the
lesson. If not, avoid.
Just be careful you
don't become a news
channel. You lose the
evergreen nature and people
come to you for
the news, not you.
And that's it.